

I design seamless user experiences and manage projects with discipline and efficiency. Born and raised in Maine, I love coffee, India Pale Ales and food that's not good for me. I have an eye for design and an appreciation of the principles and the beauty behind great code.



Holliston, Massachusetts, United States of America

# Experience

## 2012 - 2017

## Panera Bread

## Senior Manager Digital Strategy & User Experience

- Presided over strategic direction of all design and development projects for panerabread. com; provided leadership for research, strategy, UX and UI design, technology platforms, content development, and Google Analytics.
- Designed and coded prototypes to more effectively test the site's user experience responsive designs in browsers, while at the same time enabling early problem-solving and also creating a more efficient transition from design to development.
- Championed comprehensive new customer-centric site strategy using analytics insight to define moments that matter, strategic intent, key tactics, objectives, and key performance indicators.
- Directed development, integration and deployment of Adobe Experience Manager content management system.

## 2007 - 2012

#### Panera Bread

## Senior Manager Marketing & Creative Services

- Cross-functional marketing and creative direction leadership for Catering, Loyalty, Field Marketing, Retail Advertising, Public Relations, and Bakery-Cafe projects.
- Led creative development and marketing implementation for Panera Cares™ under direct supervision of CEO and founder Ron Shaich.
- Directed development, deployment and promotion of a web-based, template-driven asset management system to improve local marketing through application of national brand standards generating a 375% increase in approved, brand-sanctioned marketing collateral.

#### 2004 - 2007

#### L.L. Bean

### **Senior Manager Creative Services**

• Directed creative development and production of materials in support of L.L. Bean's catalog, retail and e-commerce business, as well as support resources for all layout and photography deliverables.











I design seamless user experiences and manage projects with discipline and efficiency. Born and raised in Maine, I love coffee, India Pale Ales and food that's not good for me. I have an eye for design and an appreciation of the principles and the beauty behind great code.



Holliston, Massachusetts, United States of America

# Expertise

- UX & UI Design
- Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, & InDesign)
- Sketch

- Strategic Planning & Analysis
- Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, & Google Optimize
- Brand & Retail Marketing
- Content Management Systems
- Project Management & Process Improvement
- Print Design & Production

# LinkedIn Endorsements

Creative Direction

Digital Marketing

Marketing Strategy

**Email Marketing** 

**Public Relations** 

Project Management

Advertising Design

\*\*\* 

# Technical Skills

Adobe Creative Cloud

Microsoft Office

Sketch

Adobe Marketing Cloud

HTML & CSS

Wordpress & PHP



# Intangibles



Strategic Thinker



**Detail Oriented** 



Collaborator



**Problem Solver** 



**Passionate** 

# Education

Bachelor of Arts, United States History Quinnipiac University





Contact Me



